Hello, and welcome.
I'm Roland, and I've created a few other courses on the ASP.NET
Core topic in the past. This course is specifically about ASP.NET
Core 6 and is created with version 6.0. It's useful for any minor
version of ASP.NET Core 6.
Should you be looking for an older version, please take a look at
my author page to find a course relevant to you.
You probably know a bit about ASP.NET Core already.
Maybe you've seen a demo, played around with it, or maybe you've
seen some documentation, but let's start at the very beginning
anyway to give you the whole big picture.
Before I start, you will have to be aware of a couple of things.
First,
the intent of this course. It is meant as an overview of all that
ASP.NET Core is and what you can do with it.
That doesn't mean this will be a course with just slides.
I also show you code so that in addition to the theory, you gain a
good technical understanding of the different parts,
just not in a way that you can code along or start creating ASP.NET Core
applications right after watching this course. You'll need to watch additional
courses before you can do that. But at the very least, this course will
inspire you to make the right choices on what part of ASP.NET Core you could
zoom into next. In terms of knowledge,
we need a starting point in order to proceed. First of all,
I'm assuming that you know how the web works with HTTP, requests, and
responses. You should have at least a basic understanding of how HTML and
CSS work because these technologies form the basis of every ASP.NET Core
application. I'm going to show you code examples. To understand them, I
also need you to know what .NET is, and you should be able to read the C#
programming language.
If you have knowledge gaps,
I would recommend watching other big picture courses around these topics
first. Depending on your learning style, looking at my code examples or
experimenting with them might be beneficial. If so, you can find all content in this GitHub repository.