We've now already covered quite a lot of concepts.
Let's head back to Visual Studio and see how we can make all of this happen.
We'll bring in MediatR and AutoMapper.
We'll then create a request and request handler,
and finally,
we'll prepare things so that our libraries can be
registered in the services collection.
If I would get paid for adding new files and new contracts,
then I would have made quite some money already today,
but only contracts, that's not very useful.
We'll need to actually write some implementation code,
and that's what I'm going to do next here.
So we're going to now, together,
write the business logic to get the list of all events,
and let's do that next.
So in order to write our business code, I'm going to need a couple of packages.
I'm actually going to be using AutoMapper and
MediatR as explained in the slides.
AutoMapper will be used to map between entities,
and MediatR will be used to write those requests and request handlers,
so the message and the message handler, that is.
To make it easy, I'm going to go to my application project,
and I'll bring in another item group that contains the
references to the packages I'll need.
So I've brought in AutoMapper with the extension for the
dependency injection and also MediatR.
If I save this file,
you can also see in the NuGet package manager that these
packages have indeed been added to my project.
So what I'll do now is I'll wrap what I'm going to do in a type,
and that is going to be my request,
and what I want to do is get all the events in a list.
So that is going to be, let's say, the message of what I want to do.
I want to get a list of all events.
So I'm going to wrap that in a type,
and that is going to be called the GetEventsListQuery,
I'm calling it query because I want to retrieve something,
and what I want to retrieve is that list of all events.
So I need to make this class a message,
and that I'm going to do by letting it implement the IRequest interface.
The parameter, the type parameter that is,
for IRequest,
is going to be the type of data that this query is going to be getting back,
and it's going to be a list of event list VMs.
That is another class that I'm going to be returning,
and I'm going to create a specific type,
a ViewModel, that I'm going to return for my client application.
It's going to be a ViewModel that is going to contain just
the properties to visualize it in a list,
just enough information so that I don't return too much data.
That means I'll add the class here because I haven't created that one yet.
It's going to be a new class, and it's going to be called EventListVm,
and it is going to be containing, like I said,
the data I want to visualize for an event when it's shown in a list.
It contains just a number of base properties,
not all properties of event,
but just the ones I'll need in the list here And
our _____ here is also satisfied, so this is the message.
I will also need a message handler that is going to be triggered,
let's say, when this message is sent,
and that will contain the actual business logic.
So that handler is going to be triggered by MediatR.
So I'm going to create another class,
and that is going to be to GetEventsListQuery handler,
handling the GetEventsListQuery.
That is going to be another class that now needs to
implement another interface from MediatR.
So specifying here that this implements the IRequest
handler in GetEventsListQuery, that's my message type,
and it's going to be returning the list of event list VMs.
Now it does still give me a red squiggly.
That is normal,
because I still need to implement the method when
I'm going to handle the message, and that method is effectively called Handle.
So this method will be called automatically when a
GetEventsListQuery is fired off, and this handler will pick it up.
So that is going to contain my business logic that's implemented here.
I've pasted in the code, and let me now take you through this.
In the constructor, I'm getting in a mapper; that is AutoMapper,
as you can see here.
I'm also going to be using an IAsyncRepository in events.
Indeed, this query handler is my business logic,
and it's going to work with the repositories to get the list of events.
With constructor injection,
I'm going to get an instance of both _eventRepository and AutoMapper.
Now the actual magic is happening here in the Handle method I set.
I'm going to be using my event repository.
I'm going to actually use the ListAllAsync method,
which we defined in the IAsyncRepository,
so the base interface, and I'm going to get all events ordered by date.
That gives me a list of entities, an IOrderedEnumerable of events,
so domain entities.
Now I don't want to return entities to my clients.
I want to return objects that I'm in control of so that they only
contain the properties that I want to return,
and those are available on my EventListVm.
Now, I don't want to write a mapping code myself,
either, so I'm going to use AutoMapper for that here.
And in AutoMapper, I can use the Map method as you see here,
and I can specify the type I want to map to,
that is the list of EventListVms.
And I'm going to use allEvents as the object that I want to be mapping from.
So what is going to be returned is a list of event list ViewModels.
Now AutoMapper does need some more information for this to actually work.
It does need what is known as a profile.
A profile will contain mapping information so that
AutoMapper knows if it should actually be able to try to
map from this type to another type.
Now AutoMapper does a lot of work automatically,
but sometimes you may need to help it a bit,
but if the properties on EventListVm have the same
names as the ones on the actual entity, then it'll do the mapping itself.
If we then just create a profile, the mapping will be done automatically for us,
if we define that in a profile, that is.
So I'm going to go back to my application project,
and I'm going to create a folder called Profiles.
Now a profile is really nothing to be scared of.
It's just a simple class that contains what AutoMapper should be
knowing in terms of mapping between types.
I'm going to call this here the MappingProfile class.
It is like I said, just a class,
and it does need to inherit from the base Profile class.
That's a class that comes with AutoMapper.
In the constructor, I'm going to write my mappings.
I'm going to create a mapping between Event and EventListVm,
and I'm going to specify and it has to be capable of
knowing about this mapping in two ways.
So from Event to EventListVm and vice versa,
that I'm doing here using the ReverseMap.
We'll add more mapping profiles as we go along.
I want to point out one more thing here.
So we can see here, I've used the IAsyncRepository in Event.
Of course,
we don't have an implementation just yet; that will be
plugged in using dependency injection,
basically the implementation of dependency inversion.
We still need to write an actual repository that knows
how to handle this in the database.
Now we don't have that one yet, but you can see that in the application project,
we're just talking with the abstraction.
That's what the application project is going to be doing,
just talking with the abstractions.
I think at this point my GetEventList implementation is more or less ready.
So I hope you understand this one already,
and I'm going to bring in yet another one for getting the event details,
and I'll show you the result of that.
I have now brought in a few extra classes,
which are going to be used to get the event details.
So I have here another query, GetEventDetail,
which is going to be a little different compared to our
GetEventsListQuery in the sense that the
GetEventDetailQuery contains an extra parameter.
I need to know which event detail do I need to fetch.
We have wrapped it here in a Guid Id.
Notice that the IRequest is now going to be generic in EventDetailVm,
so the return type is going to be a different VM,
a different ViewModel that contains more properties about the event,
event detail information, that is.
Notice that I have a nested entity here called CategoryDto.
I also need to know information about the category of that event.
That is a different type.
It's again not going to be the actual category entity
that I'm going to be returning.
I'm going to be returning a nested CategoryDto containing the id and the name
of that category that I need to return for my event detail.
Now the GetEventDetailQuery handler is also included here,
and I'll take you through that one as well.
It's again an IRequest handler that is now going to be
triggered by the GetEventDetailQuery,
and it's going to return not a list of EventListVms,
but a single EventDetailVm.
We're going to again use the _eventRepository,
but we're also going to use a _categoryRepository,
and we're going to be using AutoMapper again.
The constructor is again going to be using a dependency injection to later on
get concrete implementations of these repositories plugged in.
In the Handle method,
which is going to be triggered when that message is received,
I'm going to get indeed the GetEventDetailQuery; that's the one we just saw,
containing the id of the event I want to get information of.
I'm again going to use my _eventRepository,
so my generic repository, and I'm going to call the .GetByIdAsync,
passing in the id.
That is going to return, or at least it should return, an EventDetailVm.
So I'm going to use, again, AutoMapper here to map to that target type.
Now remember that I also had in here a CategoryDto.
That is not going to be automatically returned by the GetByIdAsync for an event.
So I need also my _categoryRepository to get an events category,
and that's what I'm doing here.
I then use another mapping to map a category entity to a CategoryDto,
and then finally, I return my EventDetail.
And that will work fine, that will compile,
but I also need a few more mappings because I've added here
a mapping from Event to EventDetailVm,
and another one from Category to CategoryDto.
So I need to go back to my MappingProfile, and I need to
bring in a mapping from Event to EventDetailVm, and another
one from Category to CategoryDto.
There we go. With those in place, this will actually run fine.
We can't test it yet, but we'll see that later.
I'm ready to do one more thing. I've used in my application project, now
MediatR and AutoMapper. These two packages need to be registered with the
service collection of my application. Now we don't have direct access to
the service collection inside of my ASP.NET Core application, that you
still need to bring in later on.
So what I'll do is I'll bring in a new class that is going
to add an extension on top of this service collection class,
so using an extension method.
So I'm going to bring in a new class called ApplicationServiceRegistration.
So as you can see,
I've now made this into an extension method on
IServiceCollection, and I'm going to be registering
AutoMapper and MediatR on the services collection.
Also here,
I'm returning the services to the caller, that I'll need later on
in my ASP.NET Core application to make sure that AutoMapper and
MediatR have correctly been registered.
Now it is in place.
Let's do another build, and that seems to work fine.
So we're in good shape here. Let's now return to the slides.