Carved Rock is a non‑existent company selling outdoor equipment.
I have created this web page for them.
It contains the logo,
a subtitle, and the phrase, Today's specials. The
HTML for this page looks like this.
Of course, you can find the elements of the page here.
They are styled and positioned using CSS classes, they have come
from a popular CSS library called Bootstrap. Under the header,
Today's specials, I now want to list products and I want customers
to click on them to see more details.
The products for Carved Rock are in a database, so we need to build
functionality to get the products out of the database and somehow render them
as part of this web page. The need for this functionality marks the
difference between a website and a web application.
A website is for static content.
It is made up of individual HTML and CSS files that rarely change, for example,
the site for a sports club that contains some info where the
club is located and how to participate.
As soon as we introduce functionality like getting the common matches
from an external source, or in the case of Carved Rock,
getting the products from a database, we no longer call it a website,
we call it a web application. To create web applications,
a web application framework helps a lot, something that gives us the
building blocks to create the needed functionality and to give us a
way to write our code in a structured manner so that it is
maintainable and extendable. ASP.NET Core is such a web application
framework created by Microsoft.
It gives us the means to create frontend and backend web
applications. Maybe you're wondering now,
do we absolutely need a web application framework?
Well, when I want to get from A to B by car,
I only have to know how to operate the car. I need not have the
knowledge around how the engine works and that's great because now
I can be focused on getting to my destination, and I don't have to
think about the underlying technology. With a web application
framework, in theory,
you could reinvent the wheel and write all the building blocks
yourself and come up with your own way to structure the code. Apart
from the time and the expertise that will take,
we want to invest in creating application solutions for our organization or
customer and leave the deeper underlying technology to others.
Also, using a commonly‑used web application framework like ASP.NET
Core enables your organization to bring in other developers that
already know how to work with the framework and its building blocks
making the onboarding process a lot easier while optimizing the
speed of development.
It's like if you buy a car of a brand and type you never drove before,
you already know how to drive it.
You don't have to read the manual first because driving a car is a
standardized practice. Hopefully you're convinced that using a web
application framework is a good idea,
but what kind of applications can be built exactly with ASP.NET Core. I'm answering that question next.