Before we get into more detail,
I want to make sure we are on the same page regarding
front and back‑end applications.
A front‑end application is responsible for delivering content to the browser.
It has to be content the browser can understand,
such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
We learned that one of the functionalities a web application can
provide is accessing data in a data store,
such as a database.
The front‑end application could implement the logic
to access the data store itself,
as well as the logic around it that makes sure the data is correct,
the business rules.
However, most of the time, it's a good idea to keep things separated.
Let the front end worry about the user interface and create another
application concerned with data and business rules.
This type of application is called a back‑end application,
and the type of back‑end application that provides data and
applies business rules is called a web API or,
in short, API.
Separation will give us a more maintainable application structure,
and it enables us to form separate front and back‑end teams,
but it also enables reusability.
Because it is a separate application now, other applications can consume it.
This could be other front‑end applications,
not just web applications,
but also desktop and mobile applications and even other back‑end applications.
ASP.NET Core lets you build powerful front and back‑end applications.
It contains three distinct application styles to create front ends,
MVC, Razor Pages, and Blazor.
But that's not all.
For back‑end applications, there is web API and gRPC.
And finally, there's SignalR,
a supporting technology that enables real‑time web applications.
In the coming course modules, I will introduce you to all of these.
For now,
it is enough to understand that ASP.NET Core can do
much more than just create a web page.
It is here to provide us with everything we need to create web applications,
not just the front end, but also all supporting applications.
Now that we know what ASP.NET Core can do,
you might ask, is ASP.NET Core a good choice,
and are there alternatives? Stay tuned.