ASP.NET Core is a great choice when you're in the market for a web application
framework. Here's why. You already got a taste of its wide range of application
styles, the multiple ways to create front and back‑end applications. You'll soon
see that no matter which one you choose,
the lower level engine is the same since they all run
on the same foundational framework.
This means you only have to learn the lower level anatomy once and apply
that knowledge to all styles. Later on in this module,
you will learn more about the anatomy.
ASP.NET Core is also open source.
That means it's not a black box in which you don't know what's going on.
Everything is transparent, and it's good for the continuation of the product
because both Microsoft and the community are working on it.
ASP.NET Core is among the best performing frameworks out there, and it
runs on multiple platforms such as Windows and Linux,
giving it the widest range of hosting options possible.
Modularity is also an important advantage.
It has a big feature set,
but almost every aspect of it is opt in. When you don't use it,
it costs nothing in terms of performance and memory.
ASP.NET Core is also built on top of .NET. That means that existing .NET
developers can use the complete library of classes they know and love
contained in .NET in their ASP.NET Core applications, using one of the .NET
programming languages where C# is the most common.
There are a lot of alternatives, which have one thing in common. They are
not running on .NET. ASP.NET Core is the obvious choice for .NET
developers. On other platforms, there is Node,js,
for example, with the Express framework. On Java,
there is a well‑known framework called Spring, and
there's Ruby on Rails and Django, just to name a few.
These are all great, but of course, they are for developers on the
platform they're running on. The bottom line, ASP.NET Core is the web application framework for .NET developers.