ASP.NET Core can be developed using the tools used to develop any .NET
application. The most commonly used is Visual Studio by Microsoft.
It comes in a number of editions.
The downside of Visual Studio is that it only runs on Windows.
There is a separately developed Mac version, however,
with a slightly different development experience in which not all
the features of the Windows version are available.
Rider by JetBrains is an alternative to Visual Studio.
It runs cross platform on Windows,
Linux, and macOS, offering the same developer
experience across the different platforms.
Visual Studio and Rider are called IDEs, integrated development environments.
They have support for everything a developer needs such
as the ability to write and edit code, build it,
run it, debug it, and deploy it.
Visual Studio Code is also commonly used, but it is
different. It focuses more on code editing,
not just of the .NET languages,
but almost every programming language in existence.
You can still do all the other things I mentioned,
but it is not integrated in the tool, and that's why Visual Studio Code
is often used together with the command line interface or CLI tools .NET
offers. .NET on the command line is part of the software development
kit, or SDK, of .NET, and it can do a lot of things like create a new
build or running the code. Since it's the most commonly used tool among
.NET developers, I will use Visual Studio during the coming code examples. In the next clip, we'll see how an ASP.NET Core application starts up.