To explain the commonalities across all styles of ASP.NET Core applications,
I'm using the application you start out with when you start a new
ASP.NET Core application with Visual Studio. Every ASP.NET Core
application starts its life as a normal command line application.
When the application is started,
the code in Program.cs is executed. First, a builder object
is created, which is then used to get an app object, which
is finally commanded to run.
Once run is executed, the command line application has turned into
an ASP.NET Core application. Let's run it and see what happens. In
Visual Studio, that is done by pressing the run button, which will
start a debugging session.
But when using a code editor,
it is also possible to open up a terminal and type .NET run using
.NET's CLI tools I mentioned earlier. The browser is opened, showing
the default web page. But there is also another application running,
which looks like a console application.
There is some logging. It seems to listen on the URL
that matches the URL in the browser.
So that means that our web application contains its own web
server, and browsers can talk to it directly.
This built‑in web server is called Kestrel. Kestrel is great because
developers now don't have to be concerned about configuring a web
server to run the application on while developing the application.
They can simply run the project.
However,
when running application in production, Kestrel often doesn't suffice because
it's likely that you have multiple web applications running on one server, and
you want to have a single place to manage and monitor them, or maybe
scalability is needed or other web server features Kestrel likes. In that case,
it is a possibility to put a web server in front of your application such as
IIS when you're on Windows.
It is used as an example on this slide,
but NGINX and Linux also works, for example. This web server will then
use the .NET CLI tool to run the application and keep it running.
Incoming requests to IIS will then be forwarded to Kestrel, and
responses will flow from Kestrel to IIS.
Developers can mimic this behavior at development time by choosing IIS Express
from this drop‑down and then run the application as normal.
IIS Express is the version of IIS that is used for development purposes.
Dependency injection is also vital for ASP.NET Core applications. We'll see how it works, next.