I'm returning to the Program.cs file in the application. The part just
above the line that creates the app object, registers services in the
dependency injection container. Dependency injection is an essential part
of every ASP.NET Core application.
The container is a central place in which types can be registered.
Each instance of the type will have a lifetime,
which is determined at registration time.
Once the registration is done,
we can ask for an object instance anywhere in the application.
The object will be automatically instantiated when we first ask for it.
Builder.Services is the object to do the registration on before the actual
application is started. AddRazorPages here is an extension method that
registers all needed types for the Razor Pages engine.
As you might remember,
Razor Pages is one of the application styles ASP.NET Core offers.
You can also register your own types in a dependency injection container.
You'll learn how to do that in the next module where I will show you the first demo application. I'm discussing the rest of Program.cs next.