In the Program.cs file, the part between the creation of the app
object and running it consists of method calls on the app object
that mainly start with the word, use. We're setting up the
internal request pipeline here.
This is the part where we're opting in on the ASP.NET Core features.
Once a request reaches our application through Kestrel,
it is processed by a number of steps that make up the request pipeline.
These steps are called middleware.
All middleware in order will have the chance to do something
with the request, forming the response.
If you don't configure any middleware in your application,
your application would simply do nothing when it receives a request.
We have to plug in middleware for routing, which maps the URL used in the
browser to a part in our application. And when we want to make static files,
such as images and CSS and JavaScript files available,
there is middleware for that.
The same goes for authorization.
So in the code, you'll find UseRouting, UseStaticFiles, and UseAuthorization,
which are all extension methods that set up the middleware in the pipeline.
UseRouting, in this case, enables a general routing
feature, and MapRazorPages will make sure that the URL is
mapped to a corresponding Razor page.
This last part is specific for the application style, RazorPages.
The order in which middleware is plugged in is important since the
request data travels through the middleware in sequence. Before showing a
Razor page at all, you want to do authorization,
for example. There's something else to say about the StaticFiles
middleware. Only files present in the wwwroot folder can be accessed by
this middleware, so all static files should be in there.
All other files in the project cannot be downloaded directly.
There are many more examples of building middleware,
and there's also the possibility to create your own. You'll see the way to write the UI part of an ASP.NET Core application, next.