All front‑end application styles have one thing in common, the way the UI,
the pages or views can be designed. It is done using Razor. Razor is
basically HTML with the option to embed C# code. To show you what I mean,
here's the file called Error.cshtml from our Razor Pages example project. The
Razor Pages application style, of course, gets its name from the Razor we're
talking about in this clip. The cshtml extension stands for C# with HTML. In
the same way VBHTML files exist, Visual Basic with HTML. We'll soon see,
however, that in Blazor, Razor files simply have the extension razor. At
first glance, this Error.cshtml file seems to be just a normal HTML file. But
when you look closely, there is embedded C# code. For example,
there is this if statement that checks the boolean property, ShowRequestId, on
a model object. If it's true, a p HTML element is rendered, and that shows the
RequestId property, also from the model object.
Notice that every time we begin a C# statement or expression, the at sign
is used. If we leave out the at sign, it will just literally show
Model.RequestId and not evaluate it as an expression.
Code blocks are also possible by using the at sign, followed by
curly braces. In such a block, multiple lines of code can be
written, ending with a semicolon.
I could, for example, add a line that declares an error text
variable. I refer to it somewhere in my HTML markup. ASP.NET Core
will make sure that the code in Razor files is processed before
the browser shows it to the user.
Now it's about time I told you the specifics of the different application styles.