And that's your biggest worry?
Yes, any kind
of virus.
But most probably
something similar to influenza.
Because of air travel.
Through the air.
- Coughing...
- I'm sorry.
I meant people. On planes.
That was something you described
in your book.
Yes, a new virus
in Madagascar, say, could be in Chicago
within a matter of weeks,
and we end up with a global pandemic.
Pan meaning "all."
The whole world becomes sick
all at once.
And, Dr. Neuman,
you're also an epidemiologist.
I presume the prospect
of a viral pandemic keeps you up
at night as well.
- No.
- No?
- All right, well, that's our show.
No, mankind has been
at war with the virus from the start.
Sometimes, millions of people die,
as in an actual war.
But in the end, we always win.
Just to be clear, you do think
microorganisms pose a threat.
Oh, in the most dire terms.
- Bacteria.
- No.
- You like saying no.
- Yes.
Not bacteria. Not viruses.
- So?
- Fungus.
Yes, that's the usual response.
Fungi seem harmless enough.
Many species know otherwise.
Because there are some fungi
who seek not to kill,
but to control.
Let me ask you,
where do we get LSD from?
Where do you get it from?
It comes from ergot, a fungus.
Psilocybin, also a fungus.
Viruses can make us ill,
but fungi can alter our very minds.
There's a fungus that infects insects.
Gets inside an ant, for example,
travels through its circulatory system
to the ant's brain,
and then floods it with hallucinogens,
thus bending the ant's mind to its will.
The fungus starts to direct
the ant's behavior,
telling it where to go, what to do,
like a puppeteer with a marionette.
And it gets worse.
The fungus needs food to live,
so it begins to devour
its host from within,
replacing the ant's flesh with its own,
but it doesn't let its victim die.
No, it keeps its puppet alive
by preventing decomposition.
- How? Where do we get penicillin from?
- Fungus.
Dr. Schoenheiss, you're in distress.
Fungal infection of this kind is real,
but not in humans.
True, fungi cannot survive
if its host's internal temperature
is over 94 degrees.
And currently, there are no reasons
for fungi to evolve
to be able to withstand
higher temperatures.
But what if that were to change?
What if, for instance,
the world were to get slightly warmer?
Well, now there is reason to evolve.
One gene mutates and an ascomycete,
candida, ergot,
cordyceps, aspergillus,
any one of them could become
capable of burrowing into our brains
and taking control,
not of millions of us,
but billions of us.
Billions of puppets with poisoned minds
permanently fixed on one unifying goal:
to spread the infection
to every last human alive
by any means necessary.
And there are no treatments for this.
No preventatives, no cures.
They don't exist.
It's not even possible to make them.
So, if that happens...
We lose.
We'll be back.
Alarm.
Alarm!
- Where's the pancake mix?
- Oh, was I...
Yeah, I was. Sorry.
I was gonna make you birthday pancakes.
I swear.
You know I don't really like pancakes.
I know you don't like them.
It was for my benefit.
Vitamin C.
You get your homework done?
Fractions?
- How old are you again?
- Thirty-six.
- You're gonna have to wear diapers soon.
- Who says I don't already?
Shell.
Calcium.
Lovely.
Is there enough for Uncle Tommy?
Well, there would've been.
Hey.
You're still alive, you old fucker.
Aw. He loves you.
He's dependent on me. Not the same.
I think it's the same.
It's definitely the same.
I thought we was having pancakes.
We'll pick you somethin' up on the road.
- Concrete guys gonna be there?
- Yeah, they said maybe.
Maybe? We can't frame until we pour.
We're not getting paid until we frame.
Well, we could bring someone else on,
get the job done faster.
No, no. I'm not splitting this job.
I barely wanna split it with you.
We could work a double.
- Literally? Today?
- I know. I'll be done by 9:00.
By 9:00, right?
Yeah.
I'll bring back a cake.
I promise.
...continued
disturbances in Jakarta,
but are advising US citizens...
Jakarta. Where is that, Middle East?
It doesn't ring a bell.
It's definitely a country.
- Or maybe part of Asia?
- Jakarta isn't a country.
Being a part of Asia isn't
mutually exclusive with being a country,
and in fact,
it's the capital of Indonesia.
Shit. Hope for us yet.
All right.
Finish up quick, we'll drop you off.
- I'm still eating my eggshells.
- You got seven minutes.
Your t-shirt's inside out.
Shit.
He's losing it.
Sarah!
Hey, neighbor!
Oh, hi.
Connie was asking after you,
since you haven't been over in a while.
You make 'em happy.
I could come by after school,
but just for, like, a little bit.
She'll take whatcha got.
Y'all can bake or whatever.
Speaking of,
we got a lot of extra here.
Y'all want some biscuits?
Dad, you love biscuits.
I do.
But I'm on Atkins.
- On what now?
- It's a... You know what?
We gotta run, but Sarah'll be by later.
She'll stay as long as you want,
tell you all about Atkins.
Great! I'll let Connie know.
Solid.
Can't tell you how exciting it was
listening to that fucking conversation.
Put that out.
Happy birthday to you.
I want you to write this diagram out
exactly as I have it.
Always subject and predicate,
verb and noun.
Okay? The sentence is,
"Where are you going?" Subject is "You".
"You are going",
predicate.
"Where", adverb.
You see it? Okay.
I have some nods, shaking of heads.
I swear you will use this later in life.
Believe me, that's why you're here.
Okay? So...
Yes, you need
to know this!
Yes, it's on your test next week!
Homework is due end of class tomorrow!
Twenty.
That's it?
Okay, 30.
Twenty's good.
It's a spring. I'll do it right now.
All day. I swear.
We're closing.
We're done for today.
It's 3:15, we close at 7:00.
- I'm very sorry. He cannot finish.
- I'm already finished.
You should go home.
- There you are, sweetie.
- Sorry.
I was getting worried.
I was getting something for my dad.
Hi, Mercy.
Hey, is everything okay?
Like, on the news?
Like what, hon?
Well, no, there was just a lot of police
and stuff on the road today.
Well, that's true every day, isn't it?
People out there need
to get right with Jesus.
Three nails plus one cross
equals four-given.
I was thinking we'd make some cookies.
Chocolate chip?
Raisin.
Come on, Mama. It's green.
You love that.
Here we go!
I don't know why I talk to her.
She's completely deaf.
Wanna give me a hand?
Be right there!
Hey, Mrs. Adler?
Could I borrow this?
Yeah, sure.
It's one of Danny's.
You know what?
My dad's gonna be back real soon.
- I should go.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
- Well, then you're taking some cookies.
No comment today
from the Austin Police Department
regarding a rash of violent incidents
across the city,
some suggesting a new street drug
may be to blame.
More on that when we return,
with Manuela Sanchez reporting live...
You locked the door for once.
- Good job.
- Yeah.
- It's 10:00.
- I know.
They gave us the wrong size
for the headers.
That doesn't mean anything to you.
I'm sorry.
Where's the cake?
- Shit.
- Come on, man.
I'll get us one tomorrow.
Swear? Or you don't get your present.
- You got me a present?
- Swear.
On my life.
Wow.
Fixed it for you.
- Did you?
- What?
I don't hear anything.
That was lame.
- You're lame.
- Yeah, I know.
Where'd you get the money for this?
Drugs. I sell hardcore drugs.
It's better than what I do.
It was only $20, which I stole from you.
I could've stolen $60,
but I put the change back
because I'm an honest thief.
- Hmm.
- Besides, it's the thought that counts.
And you were never gonna
do it for yourself, so.
Thank you.
There's one more.
Borrowed it from the Adlers.
Oh, this is the one
with the deleted scenes.
Yeah, imagine how bad those have to be.
Come on, pop it in.
While it's still your birthday.
- Don't fall asleep.
- 'Course, I won't.
It's too riveting.
Hello?
Joel, it's me.
I'm okay.
- Yeah?
- But I'm in jail.
- God damn it.
- Wasn't my fault this time.
I was at the bar, some guy goes crazy,
starts swinging at a waitress,
I stepped in, knocked him out,
cops show up...
Look, it doesn't fucking matter.
- You gotta bail me out.
- Now?
It's Friday,
you don't get me out tonight,
I'm in here all weekend.
It's a fucking madhouse, Joel.
- I gotta get out.
- Which jail? Travis County?
Yeah, on 10th.
- God damn it, Tommy.
- I'm sorry.
Please.
Okay.
Fucking idiot.
Dad?
Law enforcement
and emergency services are in the area
and will be in contact
with further instructions.
Stay indoors. Law enforcement...
Easy. Easy, Mercy.
What are you doing out here, boy?
Come on, let's get you home.
Come on, Mercy. Please.
Mercy!
Mrs. Adler?
Help me.
Get in the truck! Right now!
Move!
What are we doing, Joel?
- You killed her.
- Baby, I'm sorry.
- Joel, we gotta go.
- Sarah, listen to me.
It's not just the Adlers.
But we're gonna be brave,
and we're gonna get outta this.
Hey. Let's go. Come on.
Get in.
Joel?
Denise, you get back inside the house!
- You lock your doors! Now!
- Come on, get in!
- Get your seat belt on.
- Hold on.
Jesus Christ, Joel!
- You take 71.
- 71, I know.
- Daddy...
- We don't know.
They're saying it's a virus.
Some kind of parasite.
Is it from terrorists?
We don't know.
- Are we sick?
- No. Of course not.
Why did things blow up?
No cellphone, no radio.
A minute ago, newsman wouldn't shut up.
- How do you know?
- What?
How do you know we're not sick?
They're saying
it's mostly people in the city.
That's why they got
the highway blocked off.
God.
That's Jimmy's place.
The Adlers would take Nana into the city
to the hospital for stuff.
That's right. They would.
That's probably why.
But, you'd have to go a lot, right?
We're fine. Trust me.
All right.
Here! Right here!
- Hey!
- What are you doing?
- They got a kid, Joel.
- So do we. Keep driving.
- Please, no! No, no!
- We could put them in the back.
Somebody else will come along.
Fuck! Everybody had
the same fucking idea.
- I can't get through this.
- All right. Let's think it through.
- Fuck!
- All right, take the field.
We cut across
and we pick up on the west side.
Yeah, yeah.
West, west, all right.
All right, hang on.
Shit! Fucking Army.
- Isn't that good?
- It's good for them,
but that's the highway
we're trying to get to.
All right, keep moving.
Head north.
- Could be a lot of people.
- Well, we can't go south,
we can't go east, we can't go west.
Hell else we supposed to go?
Tommy, come on!
Yeah, I know that place.
- This can work.
- Yeah, but then what?
I don't know. Mexico. Just far.
- Far as we can. How much gas?
- Three-quarter tank.
Go through town, golf course
by the river, straight across,
we pick up the highway
on the other side of the blockade,
then we're out.
Maybe it's everywhere.
Maybe there's nowhere to go.
What the fuck?
Son of a bitch. Gotta go around.
Grab something!
All right, keep going, keep going.
Shit. Tommy!
Tommy, you can't stop here.
- I can't drive through 'em all.
- Are you serious?
Just keep going!
Go, go, go. Back, back,
- back, back!
- I'm trying!
Tommy, go faster! We gotta go!
I'm trying!
There's nowhere to fucking go!
- Find an alley!
- What alley?
- There's people everywhere!
- Roll the fuck over them!
We gotta get off this street now!
That's what I'm trying to do, Joel.
We're gonna be okay.
Just keep driving.
Dad?
Holy shit!
Move. Move!
Sarah, Sarah.
Stay right there. Don't move.
Tommy, you okay?
Yeah, okay.
Sarah, don't look.
You look at me, okay?
I'm sorry, baby, I know, I know.
Come here. Put your arms around me.
Come here, come here.
I got you. I got you.
Got you.
Are you okay? Are you okay?
- My ankle.
- All right, okay.
We gotta get off the street! Shit!
Tommy?
Tommy!
Head to the river! I'll find a way.
Get her outta here, Joel! Go!
- We can't leave him.
- He'll be fine.
- Can you run?
- No.
- You keep your eyes on me.
- Okay.
- Okay?
And don't look anywhere else.
All right.
It's okay, baby. You're safe.
Don't move!
- My daughter's hurt her ankle.
- Stop right there!
Okay.
Easy now. We're not sick!
I've got two civilians by the river,
one of them injured.
Ankle.
What about Uncle Tommy?
We're gonna get you
somewhere safe first.
- Then we'll go back for him, okay?
- Okay.
- I'm sorry, repeat?
Hey. No one told you to move.
Yes, sir.
We're not sick.
Sir,
we are not sick!
I'm sorry.
Please, don't.
Oh, God.
No.
No, no. No.
Okay. You're okay.
You're okay. Move your hand, baby.
Move your hand.
I know, baby, I know,
I know, I know, I know.
I know it hurts.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
Come on, baby. You're okay, you're okay.
I know, I know, I know, I know, baby,
I know, I know. I know this hurts.
You're gonna be okay.
All right. Baby, baby, listen to me.
I gotta get you up, okay?
I gotta get you up.
All right? Come on.
You come on. I know, baby.
No, no. I know, I know, I know,
I know, I know, I know.
Tommy, help me!
Joel.
Come on, baby girl.
Come on, baby girl. I gotta get you up.
Come on.
Come on, we'll get up.
Come on, baby girl.
Come on, come on, please.
We don't want you
falling out of the chair.
What's your name?
Are you alone?
And...
how did you get this?
It's gonna be
a little tickle right here.
What if I told you
that after we gave you some medicine,
we're gonna find you
your favorite food to eat?
Would you like that?
And then we'll get you
some new clothes and toys,
as many as you wanna play with.
It's just a little needle.
It's okay.
You're safe.
I can't.
Ten.
- You got anything else?
- Nothing today.
Tomorrow, we got street sweeping,
or sewer maintenance.
Which pays more?
That'd be the one with the shit.
Late crew. 4:00 p.m. start.
...violation
of EMC 342.3,
unauthorized exit
from a Quarantine Zone.
Maria Elisiano, violation of EMC 342.7,
unauthorized entry
into a Quarantine Zone.
Each of you have been tried
in a military court ofjustice,
and each of you having been found guilty
by the court martial panel,
and with a sentence of death
by execution,
as empowered under the EMPA,
Article 1, Section 5...
Come on.
- Or I could just shoot you.
- Yeah, but then what would you do?
You're short five.
- Oxy?
- Hydro.
- How old?
- Three months.
- From Atlanta?
- I don't know where he gets 'em from.
- I just know they're real.
- If it's real, it's from Atlanta.
FEDRA's got a factory
down there in the QZ.
Supposedly only makes two things.
Pills and bullets, bullets and pills.
Well, the more you shoot people,
the harder it is to sleep, I guess.
Oh, you guess?
You want 'em or not?
I need the bag back.
- How are we doing with the vehicle?
- All set.
Had to get one last guy in the depot
to buy in.
Okay, how much?
Four of them on that shift plus me,
600 total.
Look, those trucks are shitheaped
for a reason.
And they don't have
any batteries. I know.
I can see about 200 for the other guys,
200 for you.
Deal.
Hey. Do yourself a favor,
stay off the streets
for the next few nights.
Fucking Fireflies been
blowing shit up all week.
Two of our guys got shot this morning.
Boss has got us working doubles.
Guys are jumpy and tired.
It's easy to make a mistake in the dark.
Stay safe.
Yeah, you too.
What do you want me
to say, Tess?
I'm not asking you
to say anything.
Sure.
It's not like I planned
on ripping you off.
I'm sorry.
Well...
how about we just let it go?
What else are you gonna do?
You gonna keep me here?
- Kill me?
- Tess, come on.
Then, Robert, what do you want?
I want you to forget this ever happened.
Done.
- Don't do that.
- What?
It's just a truck battery.
I paid you for it, you sold it
to someone else, and you spent my money.
You think I've
never done shit like that?
- My guys fucked you up.
- Yeah, so discipline them.
Cut off a finger
or whatever the fuck you want.
I don't care. They're your fucking guys.
What about your guy?
'Cause when he sees you,
I mean... put yourself in my shoes.
Look, he answers to me.
So, I give you my word
that he won't hurt you.
I'll tell him
that I got jumped by some guys,
and then you
and I can just move the fuck on.
Now your shit has
pretty much ruined my week,
and I'd like to go home
and drink 'til my face stops hurting.
So, are we good?
Yeah.
All citizens must
clear the surrounding area immediately.
Do not return
until FEDRA authorities permit.
All citizens must clear
the surrounding area immediately.
Do not return
until FEDRA authorities permit.
All citizens must clear
the surrounding area immediately.
Do not return
until FEDRA authorities permit.
All citizens must clear
the surrounding area immediately.
Do not return
until FEDRA authorities permit.
All citizens must clear
the surrounding area immediately.
Do not return
until FEDRA authorities permit.
Shit.
Firefly, up top!
Free Boston now, motherfuckers!
Move, move, move.
They're shooting.
- They're shooting at us.
- On your knees. On your knees.
No, no! I'm not a F...
I'm not a Firefly!
Count slowly and clearly
from one to ten.
- One, two, three, four...
- Slowly, and clearly.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Fuck
you.
And hold out your...
- State your name, slowly and clearly.
- Veronica.
Same as yesterday, and the day before,
and the day before, and the...
Hey.
People are gonna come looking for me.
People from FEDRA, you hear me?
Let me out
or you're gonna pay, motherfuckers!
I'm not supposed to be here!
Hey, there's a line.
"Tell Dad it's a girl.
That would be good, right?
He wanted a granddaughter.
Love, Becca."
End message. Read back.
Correct.
73-K Orlando, out.
Nothing?
Is there any chance
it's coming in at night?
You're asleep and you miss it?
When I'm sleeping, Gabriela listens
or my son, the smart one,
not the other one, God bless him.
If Tommy responded, we'd know.
- And you're talking to the tower?
- Every day.
They gave him your message.
They haven't seen
or heard from him since.
And that's it.
- It hasn't been that long.
- It's been three weeks.
It's never taken him
more than a day to respond.
I'm sure he's okay.
Show me where the tower is.
You can't be serious.
Joel, it's in Wyoming.
All this open country?
You're a capable guy,
but there are worse things
than Infected out there.
I hear everything on this.
There are raiders, there are slavers...
But you're "sure" Tommy is okay?
It's...
It's the Cody Tower.
Q-Bar 4,
but I don't know exactly where...
Next!
Joel!
I got jumped by a couple guys.
- What guys?
- Just a couple teenagers.
Said some shit
I probably shouldn't have.
Come on. You know these guys
were born after the outbreak.
Never learned how to argue.
They just start swinging.
Fucking 19-year-old pieces of shit.
It's a miracle you're alive.
It's a miracle any of us are alive.
These aren't new.
No.
I was in FEDRA lockup all day.
Anyway, it doesn't matter.
- I need you to take a breath.
- What?
- Joel.
The guys who jumped me were with Robert.
He sold our battery to someone else.
Nothing's lost.
Shit like this is gonna happen.
Now we just shake it off,
and we go get our cards back
or the battery.
I need the battery, Tess.
The truck's no good without one
and if I don't get to Tommy soon,
he's gonna die out there!
Okay, fuck it. We get our money back
and the battery.
But, Joel, listen.
Robert is terrified of you.
So, you march out of here
all Clint Eastwood,
he's going to get wind of it and skip.
I need you to take a breath.
Who'd he sell it to?
- Don't know.
- Well, where is he?
Don't know...
...yet.
But we're gonna find out quietly.
Understand?
Now, I promised Robert
that you wouldn't hurt him.
But I would very much like for you
to hurt him.
So, let's go hunt that motherfucker down
and get our battery and our truck.
And then we'll go find Tommy.
All right?
All right.
The team in place at Southeast 3?
I held them back.
I have some questions.
Okay.
We've been blowing up
meaningless FEDRA targets
spread out all over the QZ
for two weeks.
We've already lost four people,
and we're...
What's the point of this?
Is that your question?
That's one of them.
My answer is to follow fucking orders.
And why do you have
some random girl locked in a room?
And the guys you have guarding her
won't tell me shit.
Our people are asking what's going on,
and I don't know what to tell them.
Tell them to follow fucking orders.
You two, go to Southeast 3. Now.
- Kim.
- Marlene.
We are in a war
against a military dictatorship
to restore democracy and freedom.
Does that sound about right?
- Yes.
- Are we winning?
Are we beating FEDRA here?
Are the Fireflies beating
FEDRA anywhere?
Rebellion takes time.
If you fight 20 years and get nowhere,
you're not a rebellion.
Just spray paint.
We're not hitting FEDRA all over the QZ.
We hit 'em here, here, here, here, here.
Where are we right now?
I want FEDRA everywhere but here.
I want them as distracted as possible.
Because tonight, every Firefly in Boston
is gonna gather in this building,
and we are gonna leave
the QZ. Permanently.
We're quitting?
No, we're taking that random girl
locked in that room west.
From our guy
in the radio tower in Salem.
Is this real?
I believe it is.
Keep it quiet.
Whatever you need.
Whatever it takes.
We'll get her where she needs to go.
Hey, friend.
Don't worry. I don't want anything.
But if you're feeling lost...
You tell me to "Look for the light"
and I'll break your jaw.
Well, I mean, it'd cost us
a couple of cards, but we got him.
He's supposedly taking the battery
to a red-tagged building.
But get this,
the corner of Stillman and Cross.
- The one Miguel used to use?
- Yeah, I'm thinking so.
I mean, we can take the subway tunnel
under Haymarket,
get into the building from below
and take Robert by surprise.
Pay this fucker back.
Come on.
You fucker!
One, two, three, four...
You're not scared?
Then unlock me.
How about we start with "Thank you"?
For what?
For saving your life.
I am the one who told them
not to shoot you, if you recall.
Why did you stop them?
We'll get to that.
So, Veronica...
how you feeling?
The same.
Is it gonna happen?
No.
So, can I go?
I won't tell anyone
about any of this, I swear.
Where you gonna go?
Back to FEDRA military school?
You that anxious to be a soldier?
You think I chose that place?
They put me there when I was a baby.
It's for orphans.
"They" didn't put you there.
I did.
Ellie.
You my fucking mom or something?
Do I look like your mom?
No, you do not.
My name is Marlene.
I'm the leader of the Fireflies
in the Boston QZ.
Why would a terrorist dump me
with FEDRA?
Because it's where you'd be safest.
And you were safe there
until you decided to sneak out.
And "terrorist?"
Was Riley a terrorist?
Why won't you let me go home?
Because you have a greater purpose
than any of us could have ever imagined.
So, we're leaving tonight,
and we're taking you with us.
- He's here.
- Five minutes.
What I'm about to tell you
cannot be repeated to anyone.
Because if you do,
I assure you...
you will die.
Okay.
Ready?
Yeah.
That's the one.
Oh, shit!
This one's done.
Yeah.
I know, I just... I wasn't expecting it.
Take it he wasn't down here
last time?
No.
You think he came down
after he was infected?
Or maybe down here
is where he was infected.
Let's keep moving.
It's like they reframed
the whole structure.
Probably in the '80s.
Everyone was cutting down
on apartment sizes
to sell more condos.
Oh. "This has been
Construction Corner with Joel Miller."
How far up are we going?
Uh,
this far.
So, this opens into the hallway.
What the fuck?
Someone put a piano in front of this?
You smell that?
Yeah, gunpowder.
Tess.
Well, the battery's no good.
And he still tried to sell it.
Twice.
You greedy fuck.
Just fucking help me up.
Shit.
God.
Just... Okay.
Shit, come on.
Fuck.
Joel?
Marlene?
You okay?
Yeah.
Ellie.
Ellie!
Oh, shit!
No, it's okay.
I'll be all right.
And you can't be stupid like this.
So this is who Robert screwed us
over with?
The Che Guevara of Boston?
I mean, war must be going
pretty shitty for you
to be buying from scumbags like him.
Yeah, it kinda has been.
The merch was bad,
and he obviously didn't take
"fuck off" for an answer.
- Give me my knife.
- What do you need a car battery for?
- Don't.
- Not at her.
Point it at me.
And to answer your question, I need it
for a better reason than you do.
No offense, but Tommy's just one man.
- It's our business to know things.
- "To know things."
You're the cause of it.
You turned my own brother against me.
- Okay, Joel.
- That was a lot of gunfire.
- FEDRA's gonna be on the way.
- I know.
We were gonna move Ellie
out of the zone tonight.
But we won't make it anywhere like this.
Not for a while anyway.
So now I'm thinking...
you're gonna do it.
- The hell we are.
- I'm not going with them!
- Let me take her.
- Tess, we don't have time for this.
- Oh, you don't have time?
- Who is she?
- To you? She's cargo.
- We don't smuggle people.
- Sorry.
- I can do it.
Kim, you don't have a fucking ear
on your fucking head.
Could you please?
There's a team of Fireflies waiting
for her at the old Statehouse.
I know what's out there.
We were going with an entire squadron
for that very reason.
But now I don't have a truck,
I don't have a squadron,
FEDRA's five minutes away.
What I do have is you.
And I know what you're both capable of.
For better or worse.
What are they capable of?
You get her there safely,
and they'll give you what you need.
Not just a battery. The whole thing.
Fueled up truck, guns,
supplies, all of it.
I swear.
Asshole!
You trust her?
No, me neither, but she seems desperate.
Firefly vehicle usually means
repurposed FEDRA stuff.
So better than a decent chance
of making it to Tommy in one of those.
- The second we hand that kid over...
- Y'all talk it through,
but please remember
that I'm bleeding out.
Okay. Here's the deal.
We'll get her to your crew
at the Statehouse.
But before we hand her over,
they give us everything that we want.
If not, we kill her. There and then.
- Deal.
- Really? That fast?
You are all that matters.
My team will not jeopardize that.
Remember what I told you?
Now go get your backpack.
Now, Ellie.
Let's go.
Joel.
Don't fuck this up.
Please.
Give us a minute, all right?
What the fuck...
So, what's the plan?
There's not a lot of options.
There's the short way
or the long way.
The short way is pretty much...
That leaves the long way.
Things look bad,
we'll come up with something.
We have to drop,
head to Bill and Frank's.
Stock up on anything we may need.
We leave after dark.
Stay with the kid.
Wait. Why do I have to... Tess!
So, who's Bill and Frank?
The radio's a smuggling code, right?
60's song, they don't have anything new.
70's, they got new stuff.
What's 80's?
- What are you doing?
- Killing time.
- What am I supposed to do?
- I'm sure you'll figure that out.
Your watch is broken.
You mumble in your sleep.
I've never been on the other side
of the wall.
Look how dark it is.
You guys go out there a lot?
- I guess.
- When was the last time?
Maybe a year. What's it matter?
But you know where to go.
So we're gonna be okay.
Yeah.
So what's the deal with you anyway?
You some kinda bigwig's daughter
or something?
Something like that.
The radio came on
when you were sleeping.
What? What was the song?
He kept saying like,
"Wake me up before you go-go"?
Shit.
Gotcha.
80's means trouble.
Code broken.
Listen...
The spot under Lancaster looks good.
- You got a jacket in your pack?
- Yeah.
Okay, get it. It's time to go.
...mandatory curfew
to fight the infection and insurrection.
Observe mandatory curfew
to fight infection and insurrection.
Holy shit. I'm actually outside.
- Jesus Christ.
- Oh, shit.
Okay, we're gonna take
the left edge around the buffer zone.
You stay close and you follow my lead.
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
Let's go.
What the hell?
Hey! Don't move.
Don't move!
You gotta be shitting me.
- Okay, let's talk this out.
- Turn around.
- Hold on...
- Get on your fucking knees.
- Now hold on...
- What did I fucking tell you, man?
I said stay the fuck home.
Get on your knees!
Just get on your knees.
Listen, you let us do this run,
we'll split the cards with you.
- Oh, will you?
- Yeah.
I'm so blessed.
Hands on your head. Eyes forward.
Hands on your head!
- Really, man?
- Yep. We're doing this by the book.
Jesus Christ.
All right. What about three-quarters?
Unauthorized exit.
They'll hang you for that.
Fine. Everything off of this run,
- and half off on all of the pills.
- Half off?
All off.
Risk my job for half off.
Out of your fucking mind.
Ellie! Ellie, what the...
Fucking bitch!
- Get out of the fucking way!
- Whoa. Whoa.
We can fix this.
Move.
No, no! No, I'm not sick!
- Joel! Joel!
- I am not sick!
Look! Look! This is three weeks old.
Nobody lasts more than a day!
Does this look a day old to you?
- You would've killed me!
- I should fucking kill you!
When did it happen?
It doesn't matter.
You have to trust me!
They're gonna catch us if we don't run!
Joel, we gotta move.
We gotta move, Joel!
Joel!
I'm taking a ride with my best friend
I hope he never lets me down again
He knows where he's taking me
Taking me where I want to be
I'm taking a ride with my best friend
We're flying high
We're watching the world pass us by
Never want to come down
Never want to put my feet back
Down on the ground