Hello. I'm Roland Guijt, and welcome to my course, ASP.NET Core 6: Big
Picture. I'm a Microsoft MVP, independent consultant, and trainer based in
the Netherlands. If you want to know what ASP.NET Core is and what you can
do with it, this course is for you. We're covering technologies like Blazor,
MVC, Web API, gRPC, and SignalR, and I'm showing you sample applications for
each, explaining them step‑by‑step. Here, are some major topics I will talk
about, server‑rendered frontend applications with MVC and Razor pages,
client‑rendered frontend applications with Blazor, and backend APIs
with gRPC and Web API. By the end of this course, you'll be able to
determine if ASP.NET Core is for you, and more importantly, what it
contains and how each contained technology works. Before beginning
the course,
you should have a good understanding on how the web works with requests and
responses, have HTML knowledge, and experience with .NET and C#. Get ready
to unlock the wonderful world of ASP.NET Core with my course, ASP.NET Core 6: Big Picture, at Pluralsight.